Finding Aid for the Philippine Zines Collection LSC.2281
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Split, 2014; Lozendo, Lyra Camille; Refareal, Gerldine; dela Cruz, Tracey (Box 7, Folder 31)
  Adultery; Death; Mental Health; Murder; Literature; psychology; Religion
- Squiggly Lines, 2017; Balita, Nino (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Niño Balita's artbook, in which he used squiggly lines to portray images from pop culture. Balita claims that this artbook is full of imperfections, but embraces it as a reflection of who he is as an artist.
  Art Book; Artists; Art
- State Of The Art, 2017; de Leon, Marguerite Alcazaren (Box 7, Folder 33)
  A mini-collection of standalone stories and illustrations. The first story is about an artist who makes and burns effigies of the Philippine president as an act of protest, but finds himself questioning the passion behind his work while attending a high-art gala. The second is about a Filipino backpacker in Thailand who realized they didn't have to travel that distance to see what was in front of them. And the last is about a lovelorn kindergarten teacher who takes extra meaures to secure a good love life, which backfires on her.
  Travel; Stalking; Effigy; Art; Colonization; Literature; Philosophy; Politics
- Stories, 2012; Cham, Rob (Box 7, Folder 34)
  This is a collection of short comic strips that are mostly auto-biographical, highlighting some dilemmas that Rob's been going through, but partly things he's never done or experienced. It's a mish-mash of humorous comic strips on how to navigate life, freelancing, and drawing for drawing's sake.
  Autobiography; Comic strips.; Business
- S-Town, undated; Nisperos, Mayelle (Box 7, Folder 35)
  A series of poems about a girl who shuns the expectations of the Catholic church and practice for her to be demure and chaste. The poems indicate that her behavior is rooted in her mother's, because her mother's implied promiscuity
  Catholicism; Sexuality; Literature; Religion
- Street Dogs of Manila, 2017; Paredes, Alexandra; Cubaohaus (Box 7, Folder 36)
  A photozine in black and white featuring the many street dogs, or "askal," that roam the streets of Manila.
  Photography; Manila (Philippines); Street dogs; Askal; Art; Geography
- the stories they tell., 2017; Kasarianlan (Box 8, Folder 24)
  Stories shared between members of Kasarianlan, an LGBT group that promotes gender equality and offers a safe space in the Polytechnic University of the Philippines. The stories are told through some photographs and sparse sentences that revolve around insecurity and intimacy.
  LGBT; Intimacy; Culture; Literature; Polytechnic University of the Philippines
- subset, 2013; De Gala, Ched (Box 7, Folder 37)
  This zine shows 7 different perspectives of a person. The perspectives are disorienting, but all allude to the main chracter having multile personality disorder.
  Multiple Personality; Art; psychology
- Substitute Substitution, undated; Esguerra, James; Neil DC (Box 7, Folder 38)
  The pages in this item include doodles, screenshots, and photos of various elements from the death/doom metal subculture scene. Some pages entail mature, raw, and gritty imagery that include swatsikas, body gore, and antichrist imagery.
  Punk; Hardcore (Music); Anarchism; Nazism; Death Metal (Music); Culture; Music; Religion
- SUKSOK SUPSOP, 2014; Mendoza, Pamela A. (Box 7, Folder 39)
  The title of this zine translates to "to stick in between, to suck." The zine contains five Tagalog poems, and two English ones.
  Poetry; Sexuality; Literature; psychology
- Summer cum Landi, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Super Soft, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Swill!, undated; Dela Cruz, Tish (Box 7, Folder 40)
  From spring chickens, to grandparents, to womanhood, Swill is a collection of short poems. As the title implies, it is a poem dump of sorts.
  Womanhood; Literature
- Talinhaga: A Journey Through Words, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  This is a zine by an anonymous creator. It delves into the topics of expecations, worth, and depression leading into suicidal ideation. Taking a dictionary-like format, each page has a word in Baybayin and Filipino, followed by an English translation and definition.
  Depression; Suicide; Baybayin; Colonization; Health; Language; psychology
- Talulikas, 2013; Aquino, Ardie; Bacani, Jose (Box 8, Folder 2)
  This contains the creation story of supernatural beings in the Philippines. It begins by explaining why these creatures ceased to walk among humans, and goes into introducing and describing the powers, appearance, and temperament of the many, different supernatural creatures in the Philippines. The creatures featured and illustrated are: tikbalang, kapre, duwende, mambabarang, babaeng nakaputi, sarangay, siyokoy, nuno sa punso, tiyanak, manananggal, tiyanak, santelmo, ang pugot, aswang, sirena, bakunawa, mangkukulam, bungisngis, batibat, and diwata.
  Supernatural; Horror; Social life and customs; Art; Culture; Folklore
- Teaching Exhibitions vol.3, 2017; Acuin, Lara; De Ocampo, Iris; Estrada, Rica (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Attitude of the Mind, the third volume to Teaching Exhibitions, inspires the way art is taught and consumed to include "listening to" and not just "looking at" the art. This zine introduces the student to the life, work, and music of the Filipino composer and ethnomusicologist José Maceda.
  Ethnomusicology; Avant-garde; Musicology; Art; Colonization; Culture; Education; History; Music; Maceda, José
- The Terms of Coexistence, 2013 December; Ligot, Kabel Mishka (Box 8, Folder 25)
  This zine mimics the form of a letter. By breaking down language, it mimics an English language lesson, and exposes that, collaged words photocopied together. Exposes the pain of war through language. The terms of coexistence between a native language and a colonized one.
  War; Colonization; History; Language; Literature; psychology
- Theo, undated; Villacorta, Claire (Box 8, Folder 28)
  'Theo' is a four-part play about a graduate student faced with a writing block for his thesis.
  Graduate School Life; Thesis; Literature
- This Won't Sell Well, 2017; Custodio, Gioseppe (Box 8, Folder 29)
  This is a compilation of daily drawings for the month of February.
  Autobiography; Freelance; Art; Business
- Threat Of Joy, 2017; Destajo, Jan Dennis (Box 8, Folder 30)
  A collection of poems in English about joy, and the reluctance to pursue it because of the fear of the unknown.
- Thunder, undated; Maris, Liana (Box 8, Folder 31)
  Stories, illustrations, and photos. A zine packed with a story, illustrations, and photos addressed as a long letter from L to E. The story is about a young woman finally letting herself grieve and let go of a past lover, who was also her bestfriend.
  Suicide; Mental Health; Art; Literature
- Tip the Waiter, 2014; Or, Elbert (Box 8, Folder 32)
  Tip the Waiter is a collection of the "tips" that Elbert Or leaves for the staff of restaurants and cafes he's visited in 2010-2014. In the Philippines, where tipping the service is not a normalized practice, Elbert leaves doodles and quotes on napkins and receipts for their waiter on top of their actual monetary tips.
  Tips; Tyography; Service Industry; Art; Business; Culture
- Tira Tira, 2016; Cesario, Joanne; Bacabac, Michelle (Box 8, Folder 33)
  Tira Tira, or "leftovers" is a zine that illustrates the different things and sentiments left behind as someone moves out of their home. The illustrations include different spots in a house, as well as a blueprint of the small, memory-filled home.
  Blueprint; Moving Out; Art; psychology
- Tish Dela Cruz, undated; Dela Cruz, Tish (Box 8, Folder 34)
  This zine introduces Tish Dela Cruz's writing style, and show multiple short stories and dialogues about relationships, smoking, and more internal musings.
  Womanhood; Drugs; Literature; psychology
- tula[K], 2013 December; Rafols, Kiko; Obejera, Michael; Mondragon (Box 8, Folder 35)
  Tula[K] is a play on the words "tula" which means poem, and "tulak" which means push. This zine contains poems about drug pushers and users in the Philippines. The stories and poems are about "tambays" or loiterers who are jobless and/or uneducated, and push or use drugs due to the lack of activity to do.
  Drugs; Drug Dealers; Tambay; Literature
- Tulala, 2013 December; UP UGAT (Box 8, Folder 36)
  In a fast-paced, non-stop world, there is rarely any chance to stop and stare. This zine provides short poems that provides the chance to pay attention to our surroundings, and the chance to observe what we are going through.
  Stress, Psychological; Literature; Politics; University of the Philippines
- Tumbleweed, 2012; dela Cruz, Ainne Frances (Box 8, Folder 37)
  This tiny zine contains a short, lyrical story about a woman who longs for her lover.
- Ubo, 2017; Gablin, Cat (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Four silent comics about different ailments of the body. The physical distress felt with a cough, a wound, a fever, and flaking skin are visually and conceptually exaggerated.
  Body Horror; Illness; Health
- Under Her Coat, 2014; Deguia, Rayji (Box 9, Folder 2)
  This is a self-publsihed zine created in 2014 that brings a modern take on local Filipino folklore monsters. The mini-comic shows the story of Orya, a manananggal who tries to hide her secret under a coat but with no avail, and the story of her budding relationship with a female aswang, which is another monster in local Filipino folklore.
  Aswang; Sexuality; LGBT; Lesbianism.; Manananggal; Culture; Folklore
- UP WRITERS CLUB, undated; UP Writers Club (Box 9, Folder 3)
  A compilation of short stories and poems about a childhood rewritten in a non-fantastical style. Rather, the poems and short stories take on an eerie tone, even if the stories are about and of childhood.
  Poetry; Short Stories; Horror; Childhood; Literature; psychology
- Vandalisms with Citation, 2014; Pedantic Pedestrians (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Vandalisms with Citations is a zine that reveals the tension between the private and the public, the accepted and the criminalized. Citing quotes that have been tagged onto a public space (walls, doors, etc.) is symbolic and a literal crime.
  Vandalism; Academia; Colonization; Education; Literature
- Vanilla Manila, undated; Celestino, Dustin; De Vera, Karen Mae (Box 9, Folder 5)
  A poem creatd for the purpose of being performed at Deus Sex Machina. This playful script is about sex positivity, and spreading awareness and openness about kinks, particularly BDSM.
  Sex Positivity; Bondage (Sexual behavior); Deus Sex Machina; Literature
- vitaphobic, 2006; Cruz, Paolo Jose O.; Dumpling Press (Box 9, Folder 6)
  This picture-zine has portrait drawings of people accompanied by short quotes that reflect small, irrational fears in life.
  Vitaphobia; Anxiety; Mental Health; Art; Health
- Vivisect, undated; Siquijor, Sachi; Demanawa, Sophia (Box 9, Folder 7)
  This zine contains personal poems written by Sachi Siqiojor during her 10-day stay in a psychiatry ward. After trying to commit suicide three times, Sachi had confronted some of the problems that have been plaguing and intensifying her mental illnesses. The poems are accompanied by illustrations that give a glimpse of what it looks like to live with the symptoms of her anxiety and depression.
  Depression; Anxiety; Family; Substance Abuse; Psychiatric Ward; Health; Literature; psychology
- Voice + Tree, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- What good is good?, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
- We Need No Fire To Warm Us, 2009; Balisi, Allan; Blanc Compound (Box 9, Folder 8)
  This is a catalog of Allan Balisi's solo exhibition at Blanc Gallery. The title of the exhibit implies the artist's desire to stop being dependent on things we used to rely on. The oil paintings symbolize the bare of human connection.
  Exhibition Catalogs; Oil Painting; Art
- We, Filipinos, Need Sex Scandals, undated; Celestino, Dustin; Filipino Freethinkers (Box 9, Folder 9)
  This is a compilation of satirical essays that critiques the backwards thinking, opinions, and laws prevalent in the Philippines. The first thing criticized is the opposition of the reproductive health act that gives universal access to contraceptions, fertility control, sexual education, and maternal care. The essays also delve into criticizing the influence of religion and the church over the Philippine government, as well as the way Filipinos rely on sex scandals to reprimand sexual deviance and further promote the feudal relationship of women having to be economically dependent to men.
  Corruption; Feminism; Fake News; Reproductive Health; Commentary; Satire; Literature; psychology; Race; Religion; Politics
- Weather-Weather Lang, 2011 April; Ela, Norby; Estanislao, Rommel Omeng; NMN Creative (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Weather-Weather Lang is a comic by Norby Ela that was published in April 2014 and printed in the Philippines. The story follows a young Korean boy living in the Philippines, who had to endure the floods caused by a typhoon with his Filipino English teacher.
  Tropical Storm Ondoy; Typhoons; Korean; Culture; Education; History; Literature; Race
- Wooty Baby, undated; Nicolas, Josel (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Wooty Baby is a zine that features chats with chatbots. It contains a transcribed conversation between lonely T-Bag and the sexbots who are trying to lure him into adult websites.
  Sexuality; Chatboxes; Chatbots; Technology
- the X files in more than 50 shades of grey, undated; Lonzano, MC (Box 8, Folder 26)
  The x files in more than 50 shades of grey is a zine by MC Lonzano, who strives break the boundaries that create a narrow view on the understandng of women, their sexuality, and erotic art.
  Sexuality; Erotic Art; Culture
- Yes?, undated; Your Everyday Sabaw (Box 9, Folder 12)
  One page, four panel comics based on Taglish puns and jokes.
  Language
- You'll Only Read This Once, 2017; Swann, Hope (Box 9, Folder 13)
  This is the reading data of Hope Swann from the years 2013-2017. The type of data collected ranges from ranking of books read, genre of books read, and comparison of the data over the years.
  Reading Logs; Data; Statistics; Literature; Math
- Ze Final Book, 2017; Uy, Marigold (Box 9, Folder 14)
  This features 20 writing prompts with small doodles or illustrations to go with each one. These writing prompts range from giving lines to start and end with, to asking to personify inanimate objects and give them characters.
  Writing Prompt; Literature
- The ZigZag Animals, 2012; The Zigzag Animals (Box 8, Folder 27)
  A multimedia zine series that go by "seasons" or themes. In the Orchid season the theme is to bloom; in the Moth Season, it is about rebirth; in the Spider Season is about building; and the Lightning Season is for illumination. The central theme for each zine is reflected through poetry, collages, and ramblings not only by the original creators of the zine, but also by their "adopted animals" or new members who've submitted pieces for the zine.
  Sexuality; Art; Literature
  - Orchid Season (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Moth Season (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Lightning Season (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Spider Season (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Zine by Motzie Dapul, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Zing Boom!, 2016; Morealis, Aurora (Box 9, Folder 15)
  This comic, which was inspired by the song "Labor of Love" by Bjork, is a true story from Aurora's own journey through pregnancy.
  Family; Pregnancy; Gentle Birth; Parenthood; Art; Health; Music; Bjork
- Zing Boom, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Zyterical Sea, 2017; Isip, Albert (Box 9, Folder 16)
  A visual account of dreams and thoughts by the author. The illustrations in each page are ambigious, but paired with words on each page. It is about an existence gaining consciousness, experiencing life, and seeing the end of it.
  Dreams; Philosophy; psychology